WAMC Northeast Public Radio; Records apap138
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
WAMC Northeast Public Radio Records
1980-2000
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
WAMC (Radio station: Albany, N.Y.)
apap138
6795 Audio Recordings
This collection contains recordings of a number of locally-produced WAMC/Northeast Public Radio programs.
Administrative History
WAMC/Northeast Public Radio is a regional public radio network serving parts of seven northeastern states. WAMC was founded in 1958 as an affiliate of Albany Medical College. While affilated with Albany Medical College, WAMC's primary purpose was instructional, but a set number of hours each week were alloted to non-medical programming such as musical performances and talkshows. WAMC/Northeast Public Radio is a regional public radio network serving parts of seven northeastern US states including New York, Massachusetts, Connecticut, Vermont, New Jersey, New Hampshire, and Pennsylvania. Stations and translators are in ten locations throughout the region. WAMC's studios and offices are located in Albany, NY. WAMC/Northeast Public Radio is a member of National Public Radio and an affiliate of Public Radio International. Financial support comes from listeners who contribute annually in fund drives and other appeals as well as from underwriting by businesses, grant support for WAMC's National Productions, and governmental sources such as the Corporation for Public Broadcasting and the New York State Education Department.
Scope and Contents
The collection is primarily composed of reel-to-reel audiotapes, audiocassette, DAT recordings, and born-digital audio of programs which aired on WAMC/Northeast Public Radio. The recordings include programs produced by WAMC as well as some produced by other stations. Note that the rights to reproduce or use recordings not produced by WAMC's National Productions remain with the creator of those programs. WAMC's National Productions produces several programs aired by its stations as well as hundreds of other radio stations around the world. WAMC's programs documented in the collection include 51%, The Best of Our Knowledge, The Book Show, Capitol Connection, The Environment Show, The Health Show, The Law Show, Legislative Gazette, Media Project, and many others. The collection also includes selected recordings produced primarily by other public radio stations. Much of this is music programs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by WAMC begining in June 2002.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into series by program.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted. Preservation concerns may prevent immediate acces to segments of the collection at the present time. All requests to listen to audio recordings must be made to M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives Reference staff in advance of a researcher's visit to the Department.
Radio stations; Radio and Television Broadcasting
- The Legislative Gazette, 1985-2013
  Scope and Contents
  Contains recorded broadcasts of The Legislative Gazette, a WAMC-produced weekly radio show hosted by David Guistina and regularly featuring Alan Chartock. The program features an in-depth look at New York State politics and government.
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8425, 1984 June 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8501, 1985 January 4
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8502, 1985 January 11
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8503, 1985 January 18
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8504, 1985 January 25
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8513, 1985 March 29
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8514, 1985 April 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8515, 1985 April 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8516, 1985 April 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8517, 1985 April 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8518, 1985 May 3
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8519, 1985 May 10
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8520, 1985 May 17
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8525, 1985 June 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8526, 1985 June 28
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8528, 1985 July 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8529, 1985 July 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8530, 1985 July 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8531, 1985 August 2
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8532, 1985 August 9
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8533, 1985 August 16
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8534, 1985 August 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8535, 1985 August 30
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8536, 1985 September 6
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8537, 1985 September 13
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8538, 1985 September 20
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8539, 1985 September 27
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8540, 1985 October 4
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8541, 1985 October 11
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8542, 1985 October 18
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8543, 1985 October 25
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8544, 1985 November 1
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8545, 1985 November 8
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8546, 1985 November 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8547, 1985 November 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8548, 1985 November 29
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8549, 1985 December 6
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8550, 1985 December 13
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8552, 1985 December 20
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8553, 1985 December 27
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8554, 1987 April 3
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8724, 1987 June 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8725, 1987 June 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8726, 1987 July 3
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8727, 1987 July 10
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8730, 1987 July 31
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8731, 1987 August 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8732, 1987 August 14
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8733, 1987 August 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8734, 1987 August 27
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8735, 1987 September 3
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8736, 1987 September 10
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8739, 1987 October 1
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8741, 1987 October 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8743, 1987 October 29
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8744, 1987 November 6
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8745, 1987 November 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8746, 1987 November 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8747, 1987 November 27
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8749, 1987 December 11
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8750, 1987 December 18
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8751, 1987 December 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8802, 1988 January 8
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8803, 1988 January 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8807, 1988 February 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8808, 1988 February 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8809, 1988 February 24
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8814, 1988 April 1
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8815, 1988 April 8
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8816, 1988 April 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8817, 1988 April 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8818, 1988 April 29
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8819, 1988 May 6
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8820, 1988 May 13
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8821, 1988 May 20
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8828, 1988 July 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 8829, 1988 July 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9001, 1990 January 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9002, 1990 January 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9003, 1990 January 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9004, 1990 January 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9005, 1990 February 2
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9006, 1990 February 9
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9007, 1990 February 16
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9008, 1990 February 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9009, 1990 March 2
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9010, 1990 March 9
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9011, 1990 March 16
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9012, 1990 March 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9013, 1990 March 30
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9014, 1990 June 4
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9034, 1990 August 24
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9035, 1990 August 31
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9036, 1990 September 7
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9037, 1990 September 14
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9038, 1990 September 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9039, 1990 September 28
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9040, 1990 October 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9041, 1990 October 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9042, 1990 October 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9043, 1990 October 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9044, 1990 November 2
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9045, 1990 November 9
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9046, 1990 November 16
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9047, 1990 November 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9048, 1990 November 30
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9049, 1990 December 7
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9050, 1990 December 14
  - Legislative Gazette Show 9051, 1990 December 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1251, 2012 December 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1252, 2012 December 28
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1301, 2013 January 4
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1302, 2013 January 11
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1303, 2013 January 18
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1304, 2013 January 25
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1305, 2013 February 1
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1306, 2013 February 8
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1307, 2013 February 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1308, 2013 February 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1309, 2013 March 1
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1310, 2013 March 8
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1311, 2013 March 15
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1312, 2013 March 22
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1313, 2013 March 29
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1314, 2013 April 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1315, 2013 April 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1316, 2013 April 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1317, 2013 April 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1318, 2013 May 3
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1319, 2013 May 10
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1320, 2013 May 17
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1321, 2013 May 24
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1323, 2013 June 7
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1324, 2013 June 14
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1325, 2013 June 21
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1326, 2013 June 28
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1327, 2013 July 5
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1328, 2013 July 12
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1329, 2013 July 19
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1330, 2013 July 26
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1331, 2013 August 2
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1332, 2013 August 9
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1333, 2013 August 16
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1334, 2013 August 23
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1335, 2013 August 30
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1336, 2013 September 6
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1337, 2013 September 13
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1338, 2013 September 20
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1339, 2013 September 27
  - Legislative Gazette Show 1340, 2013 October 4
- The Environment Show, 1990-2000
  Contains recorded broadcasts of The Environment Show, a WAMC-produced weekly radio show hosted by Peter A. A. Berle, former President of the National Audubon Society. The show features conversations with environmentalists about environmental crises, possible solutions, and paths to preserve natural resources.
  - The Environment Show #3, 1990 January 21
  - The Environment Show #11, 1990 March 18
  - The Environment Show #12, 1990 March 25
  - The Environment Show #13, 1990 April 1
  - The Environment Show #14, 1990 April 8
  - The Environment Show #15, 1990 April 15
  - The Environment Show #16, 1990 April 22
  - The Environment Show #17, 1990 April 29
  - The Environment Show #22, 1990 June 3
  - The Environment Show #23, 1990 June 10
  - The Environment Show #24, 1990 June 17
  - The Environment Show #25, 1990 June 24
  - The Environment Show #26, 1990 July 1
  - The Environment Show #27, 1990 July 7
  - The Environment Show #28, 1990 July 14
  - The Environment Show #29, 1990 July 21
  - The Environment Show #30, 1990 July 28
  - The Environment Show #31, 1990 August 4
  - The Environment Show #32, 1991 August 11
  - The Environment Show #33, 1990 August 18
  - The Environment Show #34, 1990 August 25
  - The Environment Show #35, 1990 September 2
  - The Environment Show #36, 1990 September 9
  - The Environment Show #37, 1990 September 16
  - The Environment Show #38, 1990 September 23
  - The Environment Show #41, 1990 October 14
  - The Environment Show #42, 1990 October 21
  - The Environment Show #48, 1990 December 2
  - The Environment Show #58, 1991 February 10
  - The Environment Show #59, 1991 February 17
  - The Environment Show #60, 1991 February 24
  - The Environment Show #61, 1991 March 3
  - The Environment Show #62, 1991 March 10
  - The Environment Show #63, 1991 March 17
  - The Environment Show #64, 1991 March 24
  - The Environment Show #65, 1991 March 31
  - The Environment Show #66, 1991 April 7
  - The Environment Show #67, 1991 April 14
  - The Environment Show #68, 1991 April 21
  - The Environment Show #69, 1991 April 28
  - The Environment Show #70, 1991 May 5
  - The Environment Show #77, 1991 June 19
  - The Environment Show #78, 1991 June 30
  - The Environment Show #79, 1991 July 7
  - The Environment Show #80, 1991 July 14
  - The Environment Show #81, 1991 July 21
  - The Environment Show #82, 1991 July 27
  - The Environment Show #83, 1991 August 4
  - The Environment Show #84, 1991 August 11
  - The Environment Show #85, 1991 August 18
  - The Environment Show #86, 1991 August 25
  - The Environment Show #87, 1991 September 1
  - The Environment Show #89, 1991 September 15
  - The Environment Show #90, 1991 September 22
  - The Environment Show #91, 1991 September 29
  - The Environment Show #92, 1991 October 6
  - The Environment Show #94, 1991 October 20
  - The Environment Show #96, 1991 November 3
  - The Environment Show #97, 1991 November 10
  - The Environment Show #100, 1991 December 1
  - The Environment Show #101, 1991 December 8
  - The Environment Show #102, 1991 December 15
  - The Environment Show #105, 1992 January 5
  - The Environment Show #106, 1992 January 12
  - The Environment Show #107, 1992 January 19
  - The Environment Show #108, 1992 January 26
  - The Environment Show #109, 1992 February 2
  - The Environment Show #110, 1992 February 9
  - The Environment Show #111, 1992 February 12
  - The Environment Show #112, 1992 February 23
  - The Environment Show #113, 1992 March 1
  - The Environment Show #114, 1992 March 4
  - The Environment Show #115, 1992 March 15
  - The Environment Show #116, 2009 March 22
  - The Environment Show #117, 2009 March 29
  - The Environment Show #118, 1992 April 5
  - The Environment Show #119, 1992 April 12
  - The Environment Show #120, 1992 April 19
  - The Environment Show #121, 1992 April 26
  - The Environment Show #122, 1992 May 3
  - The Environment Show #123, 1992 May 10
  - The Environment Show #126, 1992 May 31
  - The Environment Show #128, 1992 June 14
  - The Environment Show #129, 1992 June 21
  - The Environment Show #130, 1992 June 28
  - The Environment Show #131, 1992 July 5
  - The Environment Show #132, 1992 July 12
  - The Environment Show #135, 1992 August 2
  - The Environment Show #136, 1992 August 9
  - The Environment Show #137, 1992 August 16
  - The Environment Show #138, 1992 August 23
  - The Environment Show #139, 1992 August 30
  - The Environment Show #140, 1992 September 6
  - The Environment Show #141, 1992 September 10
  - The Environment Show #142, 1992 September 20
  - The Environment Show #143, 1992 September 27
  - The Environment Show #144, 1992 October 4
  - The Environment Show #149, 1992 November 8
  - The Environment Show #150, 1992 November 15
  - The Environment Show #151, 1992 November 20
  - The Environment Show #152, 1992 November 29
  - The Environment Show #153, 1992 December 6
  - The Environment Show #154, 1992 December 13
  - The Environment Show #155, 1992 December 20
  - The Environment Show #156, 1992 December 27
  - The Environment Show #158, 1993 January 10
  - The Environment Show #160, 1993 January 24
  - The Environment Show #161, 1993 January 31
  - The Environment Show #162, 1993 February 3
  - The Environment Show #163, 1993 February 10
  - The Environment Show #164, 1993 February 17
  - The Environment Show #165, 1993 February 25
  - The Environment Show #167, 1993 March 12
  - The Environment Show #168, 1993 March 14
  - The Environment Show #169, 1993 March 23
  - The Environment Show #170, 1993 March 31
  - The Environment Show #171, 1993 April 7
  - The Environment Show #172, 1993 April 13
  - The Environment Show #173, 1993 April 25
  - The Environment Show #174, 1993 May 2
  - The Environment Show #175, 1993 May 9
  - The Environment Show #176, 1993 May 16
  - The Environment Show #177, 1993 May 23
  - The Environment Show #178, 1993 May 30
  - The Environment Show #179, 1993 June 6
  - The Environment Show #180, 1993 June 13
  - The Environment Show #181, 1993 June 20
  - The Environment Show #182, 1993 June 23
  - The Environment Show #183, 1993 July 4
  - The Environment Show #184, 1993 July 11
  - The Environment Show #185, 1993 July 18
  - The Environment Show #186, 1993 July 25
  - The Environment Show #187, 1993 August 1
  - The Environment Show #188, 1993 August 8
  - The Environment Show #189, 1993 August 15
  - The Environment Show #190, 1993 August 22
  - The Environment Show #191, 1993 August 29
  - The Environment Show #192, 1993 September 5
  - The Environment Show #193, 1993 September 12
  - The Environment Show #194, 1993 September 19
  - The Environment Show #195, 1993 September 26
  - The Environment Show #196, 1993 October 3
  - The Environment Show #197, 1993 October 10
  - The Environment Show #198, 1993 October 17
  - The Environment Show #199, 1993 October 24
  - The Environment Show #200, 1993 October 31
  - The Environment Show #201, 1993 November 7
  - The Environment Show #202, 1993 November 14
  - The Environment Show #203, 1993 November 21
  - The Environment Show #204, 1993 November 25
  - The Environment Show #205, 1993 December 5
  - The Environment Show #206, 1993 December 12
  - The Environment Show #207, 1993 December 19
  - The Environment Show #208, 1993 December 26
  - The Environment Show #256, 1994 November 27
  - The Environment Show #257, 1994 December 1
  - The Environment Show #258, 1994 December 11
  - The Environment Show #259, 1994 December 18
  - The Environment Show #284, 1995 June 11
  - The Environment Show #285, 1995 June 18
  - The Environment Show #286, 1995 June 25
  - The Environment Show #287, 1995 July 2
  - The Environment Show #294, 1995 August 20
  - The Environment Show #295, 1995 August 27
  - The Environment Show #296, 1995 September 3
  - The Environment Show #297, 1995 September 10
  - The Environment Show #298, 1995 September 17
  - The Environment Show #300, 1995 October 1
  - The Environment Show #301, 1995 October 8
  - The Environment Show #302, 1995 October 15
  - The Environment Show #303, 1995 October 22
  - The Environment Show #304, 1995 October 29
  - The Environment Show #305, 1995 November 5
  - The Environment Show #306, 1995 November 12
  - The Environment Show #307, 1995 November 19
  - The Environment Show #308, 1995 November 26
  - The Environment Show #309, 1995 December 3
  - The Environment Show #310, 1995 December 10
  - The Environment Show #311, 1995 December 17
  - The Environment Show #312, 1995 December 24
  - The Environment Show #313, 1995 December 31
  - The Environment Show #314, 1996 January 7
  - The Environment Show #315, 1996 January 14
  - The Environment Show #316, 1996 January 21
  - The Environment Show #317, 1996 January 28
  - The Environment Show #318, 1996 February 4
  - The Environment Show #319, 1996 February 11
  - The Environment Show #320, 1996 February 18
  - The Environment Show #321, 1996 February 25
  - The Environment Show #322, 1996 March 3
  - The Environment Show #323, 1996 March 10
  - The Environment Show #324, 1996 March 17
  - The Environment Show #325, 1996 March 24
  - The Environment Show #326, 1996 March 31
  - The Environment Show #327, 1996 April 7
  - The Environment Show #328, 1996 April 14
  - The Environment Show #329, 1996 April 21
  - The Environment Show #330, 1996 April 29
  - The Environment Show #331, 1996 May 5
  - The Environment Show #332, 1996 May 12
  - The Environment Show #333, 1996 May 19
  - The Environment Show #334, 1996 May 26
  - The Environment Show #335, 1996 June 2
  - The Environment Show #336, 1996 June 9
  - The Environment Show #337, 1996 June 16
  - The Environment Show #338, 1996 June 23
  - The Environment Show #339, 1996 June 30
  - The Environment Show #340, 1996 July 7
  - The Environment Show #341, 1996 July 14
  - The Environment Show #342, 1996 July 21
  - The Environment Show #343, 1996 July 28
  - The Environment Show #344, 1996 August 4
  - The Environment Show #345, 1996 August 10
  - The Environment Show #346, 1996 August 18
  - The Environment Show #347, 1996 August 25
  - The Environment Show #348, 1996 September 1
  - The Environment Show #349, 1996 September 8
  - The Environment Show #350, 1996 September 15
  - The Environment Show #351, 1996 September 22
  - The Environment Show #352, 1996 September 29
  - The Environment Show #353, 1996 October 6
  - The Environment Show #354, 1996 October 13
  - The Environment Show #355, 1996 October 20
  - The Environment Show #356, 1996 October 27
  - The Environment Show #357, 1996 November 3
  - The Environment Show #358, 1996 November 9
  - The Environment Show #359, 1996 November 17
  - The Environment Show #360, 1996 November 24
  - The Environment Show #361, 1996 December 1
  - The Environment Show #362, 1996 December 8
  - The Environment Show #363, 1996 December 15
  - The Environment Show #364, 1996 December 22
  - The Environment Show #365, 1996 December 29
  - The Environment Show #366, 1997 January 4
  - The Environment Show #367, 1997 January 11
  - The Environment Show #368, 1997 January 18
  - The Environment Show #369, 1997 January 25
  - The Environment Show #370, 1997 February 1
  - The Environment Show #371, 1997 February 8
  - The Environment Show #372, 1997 February 13
  - The Environment Show #373, 1997 February 22
  - The Environment Show #374, 1997 March 1
  - The Environment Show #375, 1997 March 8
  - The Environment Show #376, 1997 March 15
  - The Environment Show #377, 1997 March 22
  - The Environment Show #378, 1997 March 26
  - The Environment Show #379, 1997 April 5
  - The Environment Show #380, 1997 April 12
  - The Environment Show #381, 1997 April 19
  - The Environment Show #382, 1997 April 26
  - The Environment Show #383, 1997 May 3
  - The Environment Show #384, 1997 May 10
  - The Environment Show #385, 1997 May 17
  - The Environment Show #386, 1997 May 24
  - The Environment Show #387, 1997 May 31
  - The Environment Show #388, 1997 June 7
  - The Environment Show #389, 1997 June 14
  - The Environment Show #390, 1997 June 21
  - The Environment Show #391, 1997 June 28
  - The Environment Show #392, 1997 July 5
  - The Environment Show #393, 1997 July 12
  - The Environment Show #394, 1997 July 19
  - The Environment Show #395, 1997 July 26
  - The Environment Show #396, 1997 August 2
  - The Environment Show #397, 1997 August 9
  - The Environment Show #398, 1997 August 16
  - The Environment Show #399, 1997 August 23
  - The Environment Show #400, 1997 August 30
  - The Environment Show #401, 1997 September 6
  - The Environment Show #402, 1997 September 13
  - The Environment Show #403, 1997 September 20
  - The Environment Show #404, 1997 September 27
  - The Environment Show #405, 1997 October 4
  - The Environment Show #406, 1997 October 11
  - The Environment Show #407, 1997 October 18
  - The Environment Show #408, 1997 October 25
  - The Environment Show #409, 1997 November 1
  - The Environment Show #410, 1997 November 8